(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T22:36:45.027226",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
残響散歌
Zankyou Sanka
誰が袖に咲く幻花
A phantom flower blooming on someone's sleeve,
ただそこに藍を落とした
simply dropping indigo right there.
派手に色を溶かす夜に 銀朱の月を添えて
Adorning the night that flamboyantly melts colors with a vermilion moon.
転がるように風を切って 躓くごとに強くなった
Cutting through the wind as if tumbling, growing stronger with every stumble.
光も痛みも怒りも全部抱きしめて
Embracing all the light, the pain, and the anger.
選ばれなければ選べばいい
If you aren't chosen, then simply choose for yourself.
声を轟かせて 夜の向こうへ
Let your voice roar out beyond the night!
涙で滲んでいた あんなに遠くの景色まで 響き渡れ
Resound all the way to that distant scenery blurred by tears!
何を奏でて 誰に届けたくて 不確かなままでいい
What do you want to play? Who do you want to reach? It's fine to be uncertain.
どんなに暗い感情も どんなに長い葛藤も 歌と散れ 残響
No matter how dark the feelings, no matter how long the struggle, disperse into song... reverberate!
ただ一人迷う深夜
Wandering alone in the dead of night,
互い違いの熱を結べば
if we intertwine our differing warmth...
派手な色もかすむように 深紅の心臓こそあわれ
As even vivid colors fade, the crimson heart itself is poignant.
この先どんなつらい時も 口先よりも胸を張って
No matter how tough the times ahead, stand proud rather than making empty talk,
抱いた夢の灯りを全部辿るだけ
and simply follow all the lights of the dreams you held.
逃げ出すため ここまで来たんじゃないだろ
We didn't come this far just to run away, right?
選ばれなければ
If you aren't chosen,
選べばいい
just make your own choice.
声を枯らして 燃える花のように
Shout until your voice runs dry, like a burning flower,
闇間を照らしたら
if you light up the darkness,
曖昧すぎる正解も 譜面にして
even overly vague answers will turn into a score.
夜を数えて朝を描くような
As if counting the nights to paint the morning,
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
play vivid sounds.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret,
どんなに高い限界も
no matter how high the limit,
掻き消して 残響
erase them all, resonating echo!
はい、ということで！ holo Acoustic Live in Summer 始まりましたー！
Alright, with that said, holo Acoustic Live in Summer has officially begun!
イエーイ！ 始まったー！
Yay! It's started!
はい、ということで、お越しくださってる皆様、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much to everyone who tuned in!
まずは今日一緒に歌っていただくメンバーがいっぱいいるんですけれどもの、自己紹介をそれぞれさせていただきたいと思います！
We have a lot of members joining us to sing today, so let's introduce ourselves first!
お願いしまーす！
Please go ahead!
まずはホロライブ6期生holoXの頭脳、博衣こよみだよー！ よろしくお願いします！
First up, I'm the brain of Hololive 6th Gen holoX, Hakui Koyori! Happy to be here!
イエーイ！ よろしくー！ 頭脳ー！
Yay! Welcome! Brain!
はい、そして1曲目から来ていただいたのは、まずはミオ先輩！
And joining us right from the first song, first is Mio-senpai!
はい！ うちうち、うちだよー！ 狼ミオだよー！ ホロライブゲーマーズの狼ミオでーす！
Yes! It's me, me, it's me! I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
イエーイ！ よろしくー！ 狼ミオだよー！
Yay! Welcome! Ookami Mio!
あ、私...！ ちゃんと自己紹介しないと！
Ah, me next...! I need to introduce myself properly!
みなさん！ 森カリオペです！ hololive English の死神です！ よろしくお願いします！ 楽しもう！ Let's have fun everyone!
Hello everyone! I'm Mori Calliope! The Reaper from hololive English! Nice to meet you! Let me enjoy this! Let's have fun, everyone!
イエーイ！ Everyone！
Yay! Everyone!
はい、こうしてお忙しい中アコースティックライブに出演していただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for taking time out of your busy schedules to perform in this acoustic live!
こちらこそー！ 歌っていただきありがとうございます！
Not at all! Thank you for having us sing with you!
はい、そしてですね、今回はなんとピアノも生演奏でお届けさせていただきます！
And this time, we're bringing you live piano accompaniment!
こよみの生誕ライブでも演奏していただきました、ウイングさんです！
Performing today is Wing-san, who also played at my birthday live!
うわー、素敵！ 美しい！
Wow, so wonderful! Beautiful!
ファンサも素敵！
The fan service is great too!
はい、このライブはですね、最初から最後まで完全生放送、そして生演奏でお届けさせていただきますので、よろしくお願いいたします！
This live stream will be completely live from start to finish, with live accompaniment, so please enjoy!
ま、なんでこのライブをやることになったかと言いますとですね、
Now, as for why we decided to hold this live...
普通の生誕ライブや周年ライブって、ダンスレッスンを頑張ったり、ゲストパートを収録でやったり、モニターを作ったりで、とにかく準備が大変なんですよね！
For regular birthday or anniversary lives, we have to practice dancing, pre-record guest parts, make background screen visuals... overall, preparation is really tough!
めっちゃ大変！
Super tough!
そう、やることが多くて1つ作るのにすごく時間がかかるんですけれど、
Yeah, there's so much to do and it takes a long time to put together just one,
アコースティックライブなら「集まって生演奏で歌ったら当日だけで行けるんじゃない？」というのにチャレンジしてみた形になっております！
so we wanted to challenge ourselves with: 'If it's an acoustic live, can't we just get together, play live, and do it all on the day itself?'
まあでもね、歌を歌っていただくので皆さんには大変なんですけれど...
Well, you all have to sing live, so it's still tough on everyone...
いやいや、楽しかったよ！ めっちゃ楽しかった！ 嬉しい！
Not at all, it was so much fun! Super fun! We're so happy!
服もお揃いみたいな感じだね！ 真ん中にこよが入ることでいい感じにまとまってる！
Our outfits look matching too! With Koyo in the middle, it pulls the look together nicely!
そう、このカラーリング的にこの並びになりました！
Yeah, we chose this lineup based on the color scheme!
もしかしたら今ね、コメントが止まっちゃってる... 壊れちゃってるかもしれないんですけど...
Right now, the comments might be frozen... or maybe broke...
また動き出すと思うので、皆さん様子を見つつ... あとトレンド今3位になってるということで！
I think it'll start moving again soon. Also, I heard we're currently trending at #3!
わー！ すごい！ ありがとう！ 早い！
Wow, amazing! Thank you! That was fast!
そんな感じでハッシュタグ #holoAcousticLive を使ってください！ スクショも感想も全部見ます！
Please use the hashtag #holoAcousticLive! We'll be checking all your screenshots and thoughts!
さて、1曲目は『残響散歌』でしたけれど、ミオ先輩どうでしたか？
Now, our first song was 'Zankyou Sanka'. Mio-senpai, how was it?
はい！ えーっと、こうやって一緒に歌うのめっちゃ楽しいよね！
Yes! Singing together like this is so much fun!
アコースティックだと歌に集中できますからね。かっこいい感じの歌をこうやって歌うの、すごい楽しかったなーって。
With an acoustic setup, you can really focus on singing. It was so much fun singing a cool song like that.
もう家は大好きです
I love being home.
こよも最近ね 歌めちゃ頑張ってて
Koyo's been working super hard on singing lately!
すごい良くなったからさ
And got so much better!
嬉しい！ 緊張しちゃった一曲目だけど
I'm so glad! I was so nervous for the first song though...
一緒に歌えてすごいテンション上がりました！
Singing together got me so hyped!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
Thank you very much!
カリィ先輩どうですか？
Calli-senpai, how about you?
かっこいい曲大好きです！
I love cool songs!
実はあの、この曲あんまり知らなかったから...
Actually, I didn't know this song that well...
え！？ 嘘！？
Wait, really?!
歌ったことなかったから...
Because I've never sung it before.
何回も練習して...
I practiced it over and over...
マジで！？ すごーい！
Seriously?! That's amazing!
少しずつ上手くなってきたかもしれないけど、頑張りました！
I think I slowly got better, but I worked hard!
素晴らしい！
Awesome!
元々知ってるって勝手に思うぐらい上手だったよね！
You were so good I assumed you already knew it!
完璧でした！ ありがとうございました！
It was perfect! Thank you so much!
かっこいい曲です！ こちらこそ！
It's such a cool song! Thank you!
Nice choice!
コメント息吹き返してる！
The comments are coming back to life!
息吹き返した！ よかったー！ おかえりー！
They're back! Yay! Welcome back!
見てる見てる！ よかったですね！
They're watching! That's great!
ということでね、こより的には...
So, as for me, Koyori...
今日は夏っぽい曲を揃えて...
I wanted to put together songs with a summer vibe today,
いい感じにしたいなーと思って選曲してたんですけども...
and pick a nice selection, but...
結構夏の曲ってエモい曲が多くて...
Summer songs tend to be really emotional...
しっとりね
And somber, right?
1発目はやっぱりかっこよくブワーッと盛り上げて始めたいなと思ったので
So I wanted to kick off the first song hype and cool!
これをえらびまして
That's why I chose this one,
かっこいいお二人にはさまれて大丈夫かな？みたいな感じだったんですけど
and I wondered if I'd be okay sandwiched between two cool seniors,
一緒に歌えてめちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
but singing with you both was so much fun!
よかった！ ありがとうございます！
So glad! Thank you so much!
はい、ということで！
Alright then!
それではそろそろ次の曲にいく...
It's about time for the next song...
メンバーをお呼びしたいと思いますよ！
let me call out the member for it!
おー！
Ooh!
ビジュー！
Bijou!
わー！ かわいいねー！
Yay! So cute!
じゃあ、Introduce, okay?
Alright, introduce yourself, okay?
えーっと...
Umm...
ホロライブイングリッシュ Adventの輝く宝石...
hololive English -Advent-'s shining jewel...
古石ビジューだよ！
Koseki Bijou here!
きらきら宝石！
Sparkling jewel!
わー！ きらきらー！
Wow! So sparkly!
Thank you for coming today!
ちっちゃいよ！
She's so tiny!
みんな、見合ってる！ みんなちっちゃいー！
Everyone's looking at each other! Everyone's so small!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Cute!
ね、この後ビジュー singing と？
So after this, Bijou is singing with...?
はい！
Yes!
緊張？ / ちょっと緊張！
Are you nervous? / A little nervous!
かわいいー！
Cute!
はい、ではこの後はですね、2曲続けてお届けさせていただくんですけども
Alright, after this, we'll be presenting two songs in a row...
次の曲はカリィ先輩とビジューの2人で！
And the next song is with Calli-senpai and Bijou!
イエーイ！
Yay!
Represent! Represent!
エモくない感じなのかな？
I wonder if it's not an emotional song?
なんかちょっとヒップホップなのかな？ どうなのかな？
Maybe it's a bit hip-hop? How is it?
Rock!
Rock and roll!
ロックンロール！？ ロックンロールかもしれない！
Rock and roll?! It might be rock and roll!
期待増えるかも！
Expectations are rising!
2人の声にめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んでますので
We picked a song that fits both of their voices so well,
堪能していただければ！
so please enjoy it!
セトリは決めさせていただきました！ ありがとう！
I got to decide the setlist! Thank you!
堪能していただけると嬉しいなと思います！
I hope you enjoy it!
では我々は一緒に客席行きましょう！
Let's head to the audience section together!
ゆっくり休んでください！
Please rest well!
頑張ってねー！ / 頑張りまーす！
Good luck! / We'll do our best!
見てるよー！
We'll be watching!
Just you and me now.
I'm nervous!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! English time!
大丈夫ですか？ / 大丈夫ですか？ 英語話せるかな？
Are you okay? / Are you okay? Can you speak English?
話さなくてもいいよ！ 楽しもう！
You don't have to talk! Let's just have fun!
楽しもう！ Let's sing a song!
Let me enjoy it too! Let's sing a song!
Yeah!
Okay, rock and roll! Wait, rock and roll! Rock! Roll!
Okay, we're rock and rolling!
And now, please listen everyone to...
『風といっしょに』！
"Kaze to Issho ni"!
風といっしょに / 作詞：戸田昭吾 作曲：たなかひろかず
[Song: Kaze to Issho ni / Lyrics: Shogo Toda / Music: Hirokazu Tanaka]
歩きつづけて どこまでゆくの？
Where are you going as you keep on walking?
風にたずねられて たちどまる
Asked by the wind, I pause in my steps.
ひとつめの太鼓
The very first drumbeat...
ドクンとなって
...thumped within my heart...
たったひとり
...all by myself...
ひとつめのたいこ トクンとなって
With the first beat of a heart,
たったひとつのいのち はじまった
a single life has begun.
やがて なにかを求めて
Eventually, searching for something,
小さな手のひらをひろげ
opening up small palms...
君はすぐにみつけたね
You quickly found it, didn't you?
君じゃない 誰かを
Someone who isn't you...
誕生日祝うローソク ふえたけど
Though the birthday candles have increased,
たったひとつのふるさと 旅立った
I departed from my one and only hometown.
今もなにかを求めて
Still searching for something even now,
大きな瞳かがやかして
with big, shining eyes...
君のポケットの中には
Inside your pocket,
君じゃない 誰かと...
with someone who isn't you...
いくつもの出会い
Countless encounters,
いくつもの別れ
countless farewells...
まぼろしのような思い出も 少し
A few memories that feel almost like an illusion.
歩きつづけて どこまでゆくの
Where will you go as you keep walking on?
風にたずねられて 空を見る
Asked by the wind, I look up at the sky.
歩きつづけて どこまでゆこうか
Where shall we go as we keep walking on?
風といっしょに また歩き出そう
Let's set off walking again, together with the wind.
大地ふみしめ どこまでもゆこう
Treading firmly on the earth, let us go anywhere.
めざしたあの夢を つかむまで
Until I grasp the dream I aimed for.
大地ふみしめ どこまでもゆこう
Treading firmly on the earth, let us go anywhere.
めざしたあの夢を つかむまで
Until we grasp the dream we aimed for.
ラララ...
La la la...
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten by now?
夏の木陰に座ったまま アイスを口に放り込んで 風を待っていた
Sitting in the summer shade, popping ice cream into our mouths, waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな 世の中の全部嘘だらけ
Have you forgotten by now? How the world was full of lies,
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと言ったこと
and how we said we'd go search for true value together?
忘れないように
So that we won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade away,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
so that tangible things aren't everything...
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる 眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I'm drawing—what was reflected in my eyes was the ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
My skirt sways in the wind,
想い出なんて忘れて
forgetting all about my memories,
浅い呼吸をする
I take shallow breaths.
汗を拭ぐって夏めく
Wiping away sweat as summer approaches.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten...
夏の木陰に座った頃
Back when we sat in the shade of summer,
遠くの丘から顔を出した雲があったじゃないか
remember the cloud peeked out from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You reached out to try and catch it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
foolishly grabbing at empty air.
僕のは紙に雲一つを書いて 笑って握ってみせて
I drew a single cloud on paper, laughed, and showed it to you.
忘れないように
So that I won't forget...
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade away...
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because what remains in history isn't everything.
今だけ顔もなくして
Losing even our faces just for now,
言葉も全部忘れて
forgetting every single word,
君は笑ってる
you are smiling.
夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
We are ghosts waiting for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart.
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me what summer smells like.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So that I won't forget...
色褪せないように
So that it won't fade away...
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because what touches our hearts isn't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words.
さよならだって教えて
Even teach me how to say goodbye.
今も見るんだよ
Even now, I still look...
夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
at the ghosts in the flowers blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time.
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but heart.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
汗を拭ぐって夏めく
Wiping away sweat as summer approaches.
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've already forgotten...
夏の木陰に座ったまま
Sitting in the shade of summer,
アイスを口に放り込んで
popping ice cream into our mouths,
風を待っていた
waiting for the wind.
はい、ということで、『花に亡霊』でした！
Alright! So that was "Ghost in a Flower"!
AZKi先輩、ようこそー！
AZKi-senpai, welcome!
お邪魔しまーす！ イエーイ！
Thanks for having me! Yay!
みなさん、かんかんかんかん、開花宣言！
Everyone, kan-kan-kan-kan, declaration of blooming!
右手にマイク、左手に地図
Microphone in right hand, map in left hand!
あなたのハートをゼロAZKi！ということで、AZKiです！
Zeroing in on your heart, AZKi! I'm AZKi!
ようこそです〜！
Welcome~!
わぁ〜、すごい素敵なライブにご招待いただきありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful live stream!
こちらこそ、ご出演いただきありがとうございます！嬉しい〜！
Thank you so much for joining us! I'm so happy~!
はい、この曲はですね、AZKi先輩に「歌いたい曲アンケート」を以前書いていただいた時に...
So for this song, a while back when we had a song request questionnaire for AZKi-senpai...
「ミオと一緒に歌いたい曲」のところに書いてくださっていた楽曲でした！
this was the song you wrote under "songs I want to sing with Mio"!
やっぱり「夏」って聞いて、この曲は外せないなと思いまして！
When I heard "summer," I thought we definitely couldn't miss this song!
そうですね〜！
That's right~!
しかも、アコースティックにめちゃくちゃ合う！
Plus, it fits acoustic so well!
うん、コメント欄でもあったんですけど、「これAZKiちゃんの十八番やん」みたいな。
Yeah! People in the comments were saying, "This is AZKi-chan's specialty!"
え、でもミオちゃんもよく歌ってるのを見かけてて...
Well, but I've seen Mio-chan sing it a lot too...
せっかくだから、やっぱりこの夏の終わりに歌いたいなと思って選びました！
So I chose it because I really wanted to sing it at the end of this summer!
ね〜！ 浄化されました、横で歌ってて。
Right~! I felt purified singing next to you.
ミオちゃん、どうでしたか？
How was it for you, Mio-chan?
いや、本当に良かったし、十八番だけど...
Man, it was really great! It's your signature song, but...
このアコースティックとかで歌ったことってございます？
have you ever sung it like this in acoustic before?
あ、でも、あんまりないかも！
Ah, come to think of it, maybe not often!
おー！いや、しかもね、ミオちゃんと一緒に歌うことで、なんかこう...
Ooh! Plus, singing it together with Mio-chan made it feel like...
「あずミオある？」「あずミオあるぞ」というコメントをちらほら見かけましたね。
I saw comments popping up like, "Is there AzuMio?" "There IS AzuMio!"
見ました！見ました！嬉しい！
I saw those! I saw those! So happy!
ありがとうございます！AZKi先輩の透き通ってる声を、お邪魔しないように...
Thank you so much! Trying hard to let AZKi-senpai's clear voice shine without getting in the way...
みんなで形になってくれてるみたいです
It looks like everyone is joining together...
あ、よかった、よかった！ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank goodness! Thank you so much!
なんと！ - はい！ - Xトレンド1位！
Guess what! - Yes! - We're #1 trending on X!
ええー！嬉しいー！
Yay! I'm so happy!
みんなありがとー！ありがとうございます！
Thank you, everyone! Thank you so much!
もっともっと呟いちゃってください
Please keep tweeting more and more!
嬉しいー！はい！ありがとうー！
I'm so glad! Yes! Thank you!
それではですね、もっと語りたいこともあるんですけれども
Well then, there's so much more we'd love to chat about,
そろそろ次の曲に行きたいと思うのですが
but it's about time to move on to the next song...
次のメンバーをまず呼び込みたいと思いますよ
First, I'd like to invite the next members onto the stage!
ミオ先輩とビブー！
Mio-senpai and Bijou!
ミオちゃん、ビブー！
Mio-chan, Bijou!
イェーイ！
Yay!
元気、元気！元気ありあまってる！
So energetic! You've got energy to spare!
元気、元気！すごいな！
Full of energy! Amazing!
ちょっとエモくて、しっとりみたいな... - ねー、しっとりしたね！
It was a bit emotional and chill... - Right, so chill!
そうですね、ふたりです...
That's right, the two of us...
あれ？あれ？ - 袖からだったから...
Huh? Huh? - Since we were waiting backstage...
ふたりは元気だったんですね - ねー、すごい！
You two were so full of energy! - Right, incredible!
えー、偉い！ - え？偉い？ - えー？
Erai! - Eh? Erai? - Eh?
偉い！エモい！エモい！
Erai! Emotional! Emotional!
エモい！偉い！エモリスティック？
Emotional! Erai! Emotistic?
エモティック？エモーショナル？ - エモーショナル！
Emotic? Emotional? - Emotional!
はい、エモーショナルにお届けしております。
Yes, we are delivering an emotional performance!
あ、ではですね、ここでAZKi先輩がお着替えに...
Ah, and now AZKi-senpai will go change...
着替えてきます！ - はい、いってらっしゃい！ - おねがいいたします！
I'll go change! - Yes, go ahead! - Please do!
でもエモーショナルと言えば...
Speaking of emotional...
ロックンロールかと思っていたカリ先輩とビブーの...
Calli-senpai and Bijou's performance, which we thought was rock 'n' roll...
「風と一緒に」もめちゃ良かったですよ！ - ありがとうございます！
"Kaze to Issho ni" was also wonderful! - Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
みんな、「え、ロックじゃないの？」みたいな、戸惑ってるのも...
Everyone was confused, like "Wait, it's not rock?"
ロックじゃないよー！あ、お帰りなさい！
It's not rock! Ah, welcome back!
早い！お着替え早い！
So fast! That was a quick change!
はい！というわけで、夏はね、エモい曲が多い感じなんですけど...
Yes! So, summer usually has a lot of emotional songs,
次からはどうなるのか？
but how will things go from here on out?
ここからは、3曲続けてお届けいたします！
From here, we'll bring you three songs back-to-back!
次の曲はですね、こちらのAZKi先輩、ミオ先輩、ビブーちゃんの3人に歌っていただきますので！
For the next song, AZKi-senpai, Mio-senpai, and Bijou-chan will sing for you!
イェーイ！がんばるぞー！
Yay! Let's do our best!
それでは、しばらくバイバイです！
Well then, bye-bye for a little while!
がんばってねー！
Good luck!
ここで一発やっぱロックンロール？
Should we hit them with rock 'n' roll here?
え？ロックンロール？
Eh? Rock 'n' roll?
台本にないこと... 戸惑ってる！
That's not in the script... You're confusing them!
というわけでね
Anyway,
まあここから3曲続くんですけど、じゃあこの3人で歌わせていただきます。
well, three songs will follow, so the three of us will sing now.
それでは聴いてください。「スパークル」。
Please listen to "Sparkle".
スパークル [original ver.] / 作詞・作曲: 野田洋次郎
[Title: Sparkle (original ver.) / Lyrics & Music: Yojiro Noda]
まだこの世界は
This world still seems
僕を飼いならしていたいみたいだ
to want to keep on taming me.
望み通りだろう
Just as it wishes, right?
美しくもがくよ
I'll beautifully struggle against it.
互いの砂時計
Looking at each other's hourglass,
眺めながらキスをしようよ
let's share a kiss.
「さよなら」から一番遠い
In the place farthest from "goodbye",
場所で待ち合わせよう
let's meet up.
ついに時はきた
The time has finally come;
昨日までは序章の序章で
up until yesterday was just the prologue to the prologue.
飛ばし読みでいいから
You can skim through it,
ここからが僕だよ
because my main story begins right here.
経験と知識と
Armed with my experience and knowledge,
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
and my slightly moldy courage,
いまだかつてないスピードで
at an unprecedented speed,
君のもとへダイブを
I will dive right to where you are.
まどろみの中で
In a daze,
生温いコーラに
over lukewarm cola,
ここでないどこかを
I dreamed of somewhere other than here,
夢見たよ
dreamed of it.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window,
電車に揺られ
swaying on the train,
運ばれる朝に
carried into the morning.
運命だとか未来とかって
Words like "destiny" or "future",
言葉がどれだけ手を
no matter how far they reach,
伸ばそうと届かない
we'll fall in love in a place
場所で僕ら恋をする
beyond their reach.
時計の針も二人を
Even the clock hands glance at us
横目に見ながら進む
as they move forward.
こんな世界を二人で
In a world like this,
一生 いや、何章でも
for a lifetime—no, through any number of chapters—
生き抜いていこう
let's survive together.
「初めまして」なんてさ
Saying "Nice to meet you,"
遥か彼方へと追いやって
banishing it far into the distance,
千年周期を
let's breathe over a thousand-year cycle
一日で息しよう
in a single day.
辞書にある言葉で
I hated the world made up entirely
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
of words found in a dictionary.
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope,
八月のある朝
on a certain morning in August.
君は僕の前で
In front of me, you acted shy,
ハニかんでは澄ましてみせた
but pretended to look composed.
この世界の教科書
With a smile that looked like
のような笑顔で
the textbook of this world.
嘘みたいな日々を
Unbelievable days,
規格外の意味を
and an extraordinary meaning—
悲劇だっていいから望んだよ
I wished for them, even if it were a tragedy.
そしたらドアの外に
And then, standing outside the door,
君が全部抱えて立っていたよ
you were there holding it all in your arms.
運命だとか未来とか
Words like "destiny" or "future"—
って言葉がどれだけ
no matter how far
手を伸ばそうと届かない
they extend their hands, in a place they can't reach,
場所で
in that place,
僕ら遊ぼうか
shall we play together?
愛し方でさえも
Even the way you loved,
君の匂いがした
smelled like you.
歩き方でさえも
Even the way you walked,
その笑い声がした
sounded like your bright laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる
Knowing that one day it will all disappear,
君のすべてを
keeping every part of you
この目に焼き付けておくことは
burned into the back of my eyes—
もう権利なんかじゃない
I feel that it's no longer just a right,
義務だと思うんだ
but a duty I must fulfill.
運命だとか未来とか
Words like "destiny" or "future"—
って言葉がどれだけ
no matter how far
手を伸ばそうと届かない
they extend their hands, in a place they can't reach,
場所で僕ら恋をする
in that place, we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を横目に見ながら進む
The hands of the clock tick on, looking at us sideways.
そんな世界を二人で
Living through such a world together,
一生 いや、何章でも
for a lifetime—no, for any number of chapters—
生き抜いていこう
let me keep surviving with you.
ガーネット
[Title: Garnet]
グラウンド駆け抜けてく
Running across the sports ground,
あなたの背中は
your back was
空に浮かんだ
freer than the clouds
雲よりも自由で
floating in the sky.
ノートに並んだ
Even the square letters
四角い文字さえ
lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす光に見えた
seemed like a light illuminating everything.
あぁ...
Ah...
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
I couldn't understand the feeling of love,
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
but this time that will never return
その意味をあたしに教えてくれた
taught me the meaning of it.
皆さん、お待たせしました！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
ちょっと生ならではという感じで 原因不明の機材トラブルが起きてしまいまして...
Due to the nature of a live stream, we had an unexplained equipment trouble...
今のところ あの原因も分かってないんですけれども...
As of right now, we still don't know the exact cause, but...
Wow! Wow!
Our singing so good it broke the stream!
Our singing was so good it broke the stream!
お待たせしました！ 復旧したので...
Sorry to keep you waiting! Now that we're back...
改めて『ガーネット』から始めさせていただこうと思います！
Let's start properly with "Garnet"!
みなさん、お待たせしてごめんね。なんかちょっとビリビリってなったみたいで...
Sorry to keep you all waiting! It seems like there was some static...
調子合わせながら、このアコースティックライブ、耳直ししていただければと思います。
As we adjust, we hope you enjoy this acoustic live performance to soothe your ears.
はい！
Yes!
では、ウイングさんもありがとうございます！
And thank you to Wing-san on the piano!
添えていただきありがとうございます。
Thank you so much for playing along with us.
では、いきますか。
Shall we get started then?
はい！ OK！
Yes! Ready!
グラウンド駆け抜けてく あなたの背中は
Your back as you run across the field
空に浮かんだ 雲よりも自由で
Is freer than the clouds floating in the sky.
ノートに並んだ 四角い文字さえ
Even the square letters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす 光に見えた
Seemed like a light illuminating everything.
好きという気持ちが 分からなくて
I didn't understand what it meant to love,
二度とは戻らない この時間が
And this time that will never return
その意味をあたしに教えてくれた
Taught me the meaning of it all.
あなたと過ごした日々を
The days I spent with you,
この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll engrave them into my heart
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
So I'll be fine even without actively trying to remember.
いつか他の誰かを 好きになったとしても
Even if I come to love someone else someday,
あなたはずっと 特別で 大切で
You will always be special and precious to me,
またこの季節が 巡ってくる
And this season will turn around again.
はじめて二人で話した放課後
After school when we talked alone for the first time,
誰も知らない 笑顔探していた
I was searching for a smile that no one else knew.
遠くであなたのはしゃいでる声に
Hearing your playful voice in the distance,
なぜだか胸が 痛くなったの
For some reason, my chest began to ache.
変わっていく事を恐れてたの
I was afraid of things changing;
ずっと友達のままいれる気がした
I felt like we could stay friends forever.
終わっていく物など無いと思った
I believed that nothing would ever end.
果てしない時間の中で
In the midst of endless time,
あなたと出会えた事が
Being able to meet you
何よりもあたしを 強くしてくれたね
Made me stronger than anything else could.
夢中で追いかける明日に
Towards the tomorrow I chase so blindly,
辿り着いたとしても
Even if I manage to reach it,
あなたはずっと 特別で 大切で
You will always be special and precious to me,
またこの季節が やってくる
And this season will come around again.
いつまでも忘れないと
That summer when you told me
あなたが言ってくれた夏
That you would never forget,
時間が流れ 今頃あたしは
Time has passed, and now here I am,
涙がこぼれてきた
With tears overflowing.
あなたと過ごした日々を
The days I spent with you,
この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll engrave them into my heart.
誰かを
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday,
好きになったとしても
...even if that happens...
あなたは
you will always be...
ずっと
...always...
特別で
...special,
大切で
and dear to me.
またこの季節が
Once again, this season...
巡っていく
...will return.
打上花火
[Title: Fireworks]
あの日見渡した渚を
I can still remember the shore we looked out upon that day,
今も思い出すんだ
even now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words we carved into the sand,
君の後ろ姿
the sight of your back as you turned away.
寄り返す波が
The waves washing over my feet,
足元をよぎり何かをさらう
carrying something away...
夕暮れの中
In the evening glow,
日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
only twilight passes by.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks blooming in a flash of light.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely this summer isn't over yet.
曖昧な心を
Melting our uncertain hearts,
解かして繋いだ
and tying them together...
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can watch these fireworks with you,
笑う顔に何が出来るだろうか
and what I can do for that smiling face of yours.
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと
Getting hurt, feeling joy...
繰り返す波と情動 焦燥
The repeating waves, emotions, and restlessness.
衝突 最終列車の音
Impulses, and the sound of the last train.
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
I'll put it into words again and again to call out to you.
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing the space between the waves, once more...
もう二度と悲しまずに
So that you'll never have to feel sad...
済むように
...ever again.
ハッと息をのめば消えちゃいそうな光が
A light that seemed like it'd vanish if I gasped...
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
...was surely still living within my chest.
手を伸ばせば触れた温かい未来は
A warm future I could touch if I reached out...
密かに二人を見ていた
...was secretly watching over the two of us.
パッと花火が
Suddenly, the fireworks...
夜に咲いた
...bloomed in the night.
夜に咲いて
Blooming in the night...
静かに消えた
...and silently disappearing.
離さないで
Don't let go...
もう少しだけ
...just a little longer.
もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little longer, stay like this...
あの日見渡した渚を
I can still remember the shore we looked out upon that day,
今も思い出すんだ
even now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words we carved into the sand,
君の後ろ姿
the sight of your back as you turned away.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks blooming in a flash of light.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely this summer isn't over yet.
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ この夜が続いて欲しかった
Melting our uncertain hearts and tying them together, I wanted this night to go on forever.
いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever...
ラーラララーラ...
La la la...
はい！ということで
Alright! So...
カリオペちゃんと『打上花火』を歌わせていただきました！
Calliope-chan and I performed 'Uchiage Hanabi' together!
花火綺麗でした！
The fireworks were so pretty!
うわー、楽しかった！
Wow, that was so much fun!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
わー、とっても楽しかったよ！
Wow, I had so much fun!
ねー！カリオペちゃんとこうやってね、デュエットできる日がくるとは...
Right? I never thought the day would come when I'd get to sing a duet like this with Calliope-chan...
イエーイ！嬉しい！思わずもう本当に...
Yay! I'm so happy! I honestly...
頑張りました、低い声で。
I worked hard on the low vocals.
かっこよかった！めちゃかっこよかった！
It was so cool! Seriously cool!
ありがとう！コントラストがすごい好きだから、低い声でやりたいなと思って。
Thank you! I really love the contrast, so I wanted to sing in a lower register.
そうね！男性パートをね、頑張って歌ってくださいました！
Yeah! She worked so hard singing the lower male parts!
カリオペちゃん、ありがとう！
Thank you, Calliope-chan!
こちらこそありがとうございました！楽しかった！
Thank you so much as well! That was fun!
楽しかったー！
It was so fun!
ということで、ここでね、またメンバーのみんなを呼びたいと思います！
So with that, I'd like to invite all the members back out on stage!
全員集合！
Everyone, assemble!
Come on! イエーイ！
Come on! Yay!
最高だった！
That was awesome!
ずっと最高です！素敵でした！ありがとうございましたー！
It's been amazing the whole time! You were wonderful! Thank you so much!
ということでですね、改めまして、本日はアコースティックライブ...
So, once again, thank you so much for...
出演いただき、そして見ていただき、ありがとうございます！
...performing in and watching our Acoustic Live today!
ありがとうございます！Thank you guys!
Thank you so much! Thank you guys!
もう本当に、選曲神だったなって自分で思うくらいね、皆さんの歌声が...
Honestly, I think the setlist was divine, and everyone's singing...
自画自賛！自画自賛です！
Praising yourself! She's praising herself!
自画自賛するくらい皆さんが本当に素晴らしくて、幸せなひと時を過ごさせていただきました！
Self-praise aside, everyone was so wonderful, and I had such a happy time!
ありがとうございます！素敵な企画を...
Thank you so much! What a wonderful event...
はい！ということでですね、なんと次が最後の曲になってしまいましたー！
Yes! So, believe it or not, the next song is going to be our last song!
えー！？今来たばかりだよー！
What!? We literally just got here!
ラストはね、この全員揃って歌いますので、お楽しみにして頂けると嬉しいんですが...
For the last song, all of us will sing together, so we hope you enjoy it, but...
ラストに行く前に、ちょっとせっかくなんで、ピアノの前でスクショタイムとか...
...before we do, since we're all here, how about a screenshot time in front of the piano?
お！いいね！おいでー！
Oh! Nice! Come on over!
撮ってください！しゃがむね！
Take screenshots, everyone! I'll crouch down!
しゃがむね！イエーイ！嬉しい！
Crouching down! Yay! So happy!
どうですかー？わーい！
How's this? Yay!
イエーイ！いい感じ！
Yay! Looking good!
撮れましたー？イエーイ！
Did you get good pictures? Yay!
イエーイ！イエーイ！
Yay! Yay!
はい、じゃあ戻りますか！ぜひぜひツイートしてくださいね！
Alright, let's head back! Be sure to tweet your photos!
ハッシュタグね！アップしてね！
Use the hashtag! Post them!
ハッシュタグよろしくお願いいたします！
Please use the official hashtag! Thank you!
ではちょっとね、最後の曲に行く前に、一言ずつ頂こうかなと思いますので...
Now, before we move to the final song, I'd like to ask everyone to say a few words...
ビブ、どうだった？
Biboo, how was it?
めっちゃ楽しかったー！
It was super fun!
みんな、すごいですね！ビブも凄かったよ！
Everyone is so amazing! You were amazing too, Biboo!
ありがとう！「Japanese is very good! すごい！」
Thank you! 'Japanese is very good! Amazing!'
ってコメントいっぱいありました！
...there were so many comments saying that!
ありがとー！日本語ちょっと難しいデス！
Thank you~! Japanese is a little difficult!
上手だったよ！めっちゃ練習してたもんね！
You did great! You practiced so hard!
ありがとう！本当すごい！
Thank you! Really amazing!
あとENのね、ライブ8月にありまして、そちらのアーカイブが9月25日とかだったかな...
Also, Hololive EN had their live concert in August, and the archive is up until around September 25th...
もうちょっと見れますので、ぜひそちらも見てください！
...so you can still watch it for a bit longer! Please check it out!
はい、そしてカリ先輩！
Alright, next, Calli-senpai!
あ、私？もっと歌いたかった！この夜が続いて欲しかった！
Ah, me? I wanted to sing more! I wanted this night to go on forever!
あと3倍くらいは歌いたかった！
I wanted to sing like three times as much!
本当楽しかった！実は私、昔3Dをゲットした時、毎回生ライブやってた...
It was really fun! Actually, back when I first got my 3D model, I used to do a live stream every time...
あ、生3Dライブ、そうそうそう
Ah, the 3D live, right, right, right!
やってたから、まあ超久しぶりですね。ずっとまたやりたかったけど、まあ機会がなくて...
Since we were doing that... well, it's been a really long time. I wanted to do it again for a while, but didn't have the opportunity...
結構収録がね、あの、入るようになったりとかしましたからね。 - そうだね。
Since we've been getting more recording sessions and things like that. - That's true.
だから本当にありがとうございます。とても楽しかったです。
So really, thank you so much. It was so much fun.
照れてる、なんか照れてる！めっちゃかっこよかった！ - ありがとうございます。
She's blushing! She looks kinda shy! That was so cool! - Thank you.
カリ先輩は今日ね、みその5周年のライブから駆けつけで...
Calli-senpai rushed over here right after Miso's 5th Anniversary live today...
すごい！ - ハシゴってこと？
That's amazing! - You double-booked?
できないそんなこと。 - ハシゴライブ... - あっちもチェックしてほしい。
I can't do that. - Double live performance... - Please check that out too.
ね、そう、是非ですね、こちらアーカイブもあるので。 - Busy, busy! 超楽しいから。
Right, yes, please do, the archive is available too. - Busy, busy! Because it's super fun!
こちらこそありがとうございました。 - ありがとうございます。 - そしてミオ先輩！
Thank you as well. - Thank you so much! - And next, Mio-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
いや、こうやってね、みんなとね、一緒に歌うってことが楽しかったね。
Man, singing together like this with everyone was so much fun.
すごいね、あの、今日貴重な時間をもらえて本当に嬉しかったです。ありがとう！
It was amazing, I was really happy to get such valuable time today. Thank you!
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much!
いや、本当ミオ先輩はソロライブ終わったばっかりで、そっちも大変だったのにもかかわらずね、出演してくださって...
Honestly, Mio-senpai just finished her solo live, so even though that was tough, you still came to perform...
でもね、出たいなって思ったんだけど、どうなってるか不安だから、ちょっと曲数は少なくしてもらったんだけど...
But, you know, I really wanted to appear, but since I was anxious about how things were going, I asked to perform fewer songs...
でも1曲少ないね。 - となっております。
Though it's just one song less. - That's how it is.
気遣いいただきありがとうございます！ - いやいや、でも出れて良かった！
Thank you so much for being so thoughtful! - Not at all, but I'm so glad I could join!
ソロライブも本当に最高だったし、アーカイブありますんで是非皆さん見てください！
Your solo live was truly amazing too, and the archive is available, so please check it out everyone!
ハーイ！Check it out!
Yay! Check it out!
そして、AZKi先輩！
And next, AZKi-senpai!
はい！いや、本当に今日いい時間を、最高の時間を過ごさせていただきましたー！見にきてくださった方もありがとうございましたっていうのと...
Yes! I had such a wonderful, the best time today! Thank you so much to everyone who tuned in to watch, and...
今回ね、こよちゃんが主催してくれて、このライブがありますので、こよちゃんありがとうと...
Koyo-chan hosted this event and made this live possible, so thank you so much, Koyo-chan...
凛さんもあの、素敵な演奏ありがとうございました！
And Rin-san, thank you so much for the wonderful piano performance!
ありがとうございましたー！ - 素晴らしーい！
Thank you so much! - Wonderful!
いや、また、in Summerですか？in Winterあるんですか？
Also, is it "in Summer"? Will there be an "in Winter"?
やりたいなあっていう気持ちを込めて...
With the hope and desire to do it...
4回できますね！ - 今後の意向次第ですよね！
We can do it four times then! - It depends on future plans, right!
今日のライブの感想とかを是非是非教えていただけたらなと思います！
Please do let us know your thoughts and impressions of today's live stream!
ありがとうございましたー！ - そして、AZKi先輩は11月に...
Thank you so much! - And, AZKi-senpai has in November...
ソロライブが、はい、ありますので、良かったら是非見に来ていただけたら嬉しいです！
...a solo live concert! So if you'd like, I'd be so happy if you came to watch!
めちゃくちゃ楽しみにしております！
I'm super looking forward to it!
争奪戦です、今！ - 配信チケットもありますので、是非ご覧ください！
It's a battle for tickets right now! - There are stream tickets too, so please check it out!
はい、ということでですね、まあ今日は、主催をしてみたのは、みんなの歌が聴きたくて、みんなと一緒に歌いたくて...
Alright, so today, the reason I decided to host this was because I wanted to hear everyone sing, and sing together with everyone...
っていう気持ちもすごくありましたし、ピアノと一緒に歌いたいっていう気持ちもすごくありまして...
...and I also really wanted to sing along with the piano...
やったんですけど、本当に最高の時間でした！ありがとうございます！
...so I hosted this, and it was truly the best time ever! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
最後の曲になっちゃって、ちょっと名残惜しいんですけど...
It's time for the final song, so it's a bit sad...
はい、このまま歌わせていただきたいと思いますよ！皆なんの曲だと思いますか？
Yes, we'd like to sing the last song now! Everyone, what song do you think it is?
What song do you think we're gonna sing last, chat? Let's see your guesses.
Last song, what do you think? Last song!
ゲス？ - ラストソングをゲスできるのかな？ - 出来るかな？
Guess? - Can you guess the last song? - I wonder if they can!
SSS?
確かに！ - 青春アーカイブ！
True! - Seishun Archive!
最初に流れてたから！ - 歌うって思うよねって話してましたね！
Because that was playing at the start! - We were saying people would think we're singing that!
正解はありそうですよ！割れてますけど...
There seem to be correct guesses! People are split, though...
夏の歌と言えば、というこの曲で締めさせていただきたいと思います。
We'd like to finish with this iconic summer song.
それでは、聴いてください。『secret base ～君がくれたもの～』
Now then, please listen to: "secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~"
secret base ～君がくれたもの～
[secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~]
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
With you at the end of summer, future dreams, big hopes, I won't forget
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing that ten years later in August we can meet again
最高の思い出を...
The best memories...
出会いは ふとした瞬間 帰り道の交差点で 声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
Our meeting was a sudden moment at the intersection on the way home, you called out to me, "Let's go home together"
僕は照れくさそうに
I was shyly...
顔隠しながら
While hiding my face...
本当は とても とても 嬉しかったよ
...I was actually really, really happy.
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks bloom beautifully in the night sky, a bit bittersweet.
あぁ 風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険もいろいろしたね
So happy, so fun, we had all kinds of adventures, didn't we?
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
With you at the end of summer, dreams of the future, big hopes—I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August 10 years from now.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that until the end, you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's bittersweet.
最高の思い出を
The greatest memories...
あぁ 夏休みもあと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer vacation is almost over.
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, sun and moon, please get along.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
Sad and lonely, we had all kinds of fights, didn't we?
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that until the end, you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's bittersweet.
最高の思い出を
The greatest memories...
突然の転校で
Suddenly transferring schools...
どうしようもなく
...there was nothing I could do.
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ
I'll write letters, I'll call you too.
忘れないでね 僕のことを
Don't forget me...
いつまでも 二人の 基地の中
...forever inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
With you at the end of summer, talking forever.
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Watching the sunset, then gazing at the stars.
君の頬を流れた 涙は ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that ran down your cheek.
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll never forget how you waved goodbye to me until the end.
だから こうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に...
So, like this, in my dreams, forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
With you at the end of summer, dreams of the future, big hopes—I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August 10 years from now.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that until the end, you were shouting "Thank you" from your heart.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's bittersweet.
最高の思い出を
The greatest memories...
...the greatest memories.
ありがとう！ バイバイ！
Thank you! Bye-bye!
完全生3D Acoustic Live in Summer
Fully Live 3D Acoustic Live in Summer